Scene Design Document for Echoes of the Architect

1. Scene: Temple
   - Atmosphere: Sacred and serene, filled with light and divine symbols.
   - Key Elements:
     - Bell Tower: Resonates with the player's actions.
     - All-Seeing Eye: Reveals hidden truths.
     - Pillars: Represent duality and balance.
   - Events:
     - Player interacts with sacred elements to unlock the temple's secrets.
   - Interactions:
     - Players can activate elements to progress through the scene.

2. Scene: Garden
   - Atmosphere: Lush and vibrant, symbolizing life and choices.
   - Key Elements:
     - Withered Tree: Represents lost potential.
     - Traveler: Offers guidance and choices.
   - Events:
     - Players can restore the tree and make moral choices.
   - Interactions:
     - Players can use items from their inventory to influence the scene.

3. Scene: Serpent Room
   - Atmosphere: Dark and introspective, filled with tension.
   - Key Elements:
     - The Serpent: Represents inner struggles and choices.
   - Events:
     - Players confront their inner serpent and make choices that affect their journey.
   - Interactions:
     - Players can choose to name, rebuke, or remain silent about the serpent.

4. Scene: Caduceus Scene
   - Atmosphere: Mystical and balanced, representing wisdom.
   - Key Elements:
     - Twin Serpents: Symbolize wisdom and ignorance.
   - Events:
     - Players must balance the serpents to progress.
   - Interactions:
     - Players can manipulate the serpents to achieve balance.

Characters:
1. The Architect
   - Description: A divine figure representing wisdom and guidance.
   - Role: Provides insight and guidance to the player.

2. The Traveler
   - Description: A character seeking knowledge and truth.
   - Role: Represents the player's journey and choices.

Items:
1. Golden Fruit
   - Description: A mystical fruit that restores life.
   - Function: Used to heal the withered tree.

2. Bell of Awakening
   - Description: A sacred bell that reveals hidden truths.
   - Function: Used to activate sacred elements and reveal patterns.

Art Style:
- The game features a blend of mystical and realistic art styles, with a focus on vibrant colors and intricate designs.

Key Visual Elements:
- Sacred geometry patterns are integrated into the environment.
- Symbolic imagery (e.g., the serpent, bell) is used throughout the game.

Soundtrack and Sound Effects:
- Ethereal music enhances the spiritual atmosphere.
- Sound effects are used to signify important actions (e.g., bell ringing, nature sounds).

Puzzle Name: Aligning Sacred Geometry
Scene: Temple

Objective:
- Align the sacred geometric patterns to unlock the next stage of the game.

Required Player Actions:
- Interact with the pillars and the bell tower to adjust their positions.

Solutions and Outcomes:
- Successfully aligning the patterns reveals a hidden path and increases the player's divine awareness score.

Thematic Significance:
- Represents the idea that understanding divine patterns leads to enlightenment.

Visual and Audio Elements:
- Visual: Sacred geometry patterns appear on the ground.
- Audio: A bell sound plays when the puzzle is solved.

---
Puzzle Name: Healing the Withered Tree
Scene: Garden

Objective:
- Restore the withered tree to its former glory.

Required Player Actions:
- Use the golden fruit from the inventory on the tree.

Solutions and Outcomes:
- The tree blossoms, revealing a hidden path and increasing the player's light score.

Thematic Significance:
- Symbolizes the power of virtuous choices and the restoration of life.

Visual and Audio Elements:
- Visual: The tree transforms from withered to vibrant.
- Audio: A soft chime plays as the tree is healed.

def load_assets(self):
    """Load all scene-specific assets"""
    try:
        self.background = pygame.image.load("assets/images/backgrounds/your_scene.png")
        self.background = pygame.transform.scale(self.background, (SCREEN_WIDTH, SCREEN_HEIGHT))
    except pygame.error as e:
        print(f"Error loading background: {e}")
        self.background = self.load_fallback_assets()  # Load fallback asset

    # Load other assets as needed
    for asset_name in self.assets_to_load:
        image_path = f"assets/images/cutouts/{asset_name}.png"
        try:
            image = pygame.image.load(image_path)
            self.assets[asset_name] = image
        except pygame.error as e:
            print(f"Could not load {image_path}: {e}")
            self.assets[asset_name] = self.load_fallback_assets()  # Load fallback asset